{
  "title": "General_Aptitude-_CSE - General_Aptitude-_CSE — Slot 10 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "General_Aptitude-_CSE — Slot 10",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>In a quadratic function, the value of the product of the roots \\((\\alpha ,\\beta )\\) is 4. Find the value of <br><br>\\(\\frac{\\alpha^{n}+\\beta^{n}}{\\alpha^{-n}+\\beta^{-n}}\\) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(n^4\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(4^n\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(2^{2n-1}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(4^{n-1}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(4^n\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39532/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-05#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Pick the odd one from the following options. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>CADBE</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>JHKIL</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>XVYWZ</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>ONPMQ</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>ONPMQ</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39528/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-04#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Find the odd one in the following group of words.\n<br><br>\nmock, deride, praise, jeer <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Mock</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Deride</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Praise</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Jeer</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Praise</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39530/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-03#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Nobody knows how the Indian cricket team is going to cope with the difficult and seamer-friendly wickets in Australia.\n<br><br>\nChoose the option which is closest in meaning to the underlined phrase in the above sentence. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Put up with.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Put in with.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Put down to.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Put up against.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Put up with.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39531/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-02#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>The man who is now Municipal Commissioner worked as _____________ <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>the security guard at a university</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>a security guard at the university</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>a security guard at university</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>the security guard at the university</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>a security guard at the university</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39529/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-01#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>In a process, the number of cycles to failure decreases exponentially with an increase in load. At a load of 80 units, it takes 100 cycles for failure. When the load is halved, it takes 10000 cycles for failure.The load for which the failure will happen in 5000 cycles is _________ <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>40</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>46.02</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>60.01</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>92.02</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>46.02</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39612/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga10#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>If \\(f(x) = 2x^{7}+3x-5\\), which of the following is a factor of \\(f(x)\\)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(x^3+8\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(x-1\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(2x-5\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(x+1\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(x-1\\)</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39611/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga09#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following statements relating to the level of poker play of four players P, Q, R and S.<br><br>I.    P always beats Q<br>\nII.   R always beats S<br>\nIII.  S loses to P only sometimes.<br>\nIV.  R always loses to Q<br><br>\nWhich of the following can be logically inferred from the above statements?<br><br>(i).  P is likely to beat all the three other players\n<br>(ii).  S is the absolute worst player in the set <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(i) only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(ii) only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>(i) and (ii) only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>neither (i) nor (ii)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>neither (i) nor (ii)</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39617/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga08#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Indian currency notes show the denomination indicated in at least seventeen languages. If this is not an indication of the nation's diversity, nothing else is.\n<br><br>\nWhich of the following can be logically inferred from the above sentences? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>India is a country of exactly seventeen languages.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Linguistic pluralism is the only indicator of a nation's diversity.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Indian currency notes have sufficient space for all the Indian languages.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Linguistic pluralism is strong evidence of India's diversity.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Linguistic pluralism is strong evidence of India's diversity.</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39613/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga07#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>A shaving set company sells 4 different types of razors- Elegance, Smooth, Soft and Executive.<br>Elegance sells at Rs. 48, Smooth at Rs. 63, Soft at Rs. 78 and Executive at Rs. 173 per piece. The table below shows the numbers of each razor sold in each quarter of a year.  <br><br>   \\(\\begin{array}{|c|r|r|r|r|} \\hline \\textbf{Quarter/Product} &amp; \\textbf{Elegance} &amp;\\textbf{Smooth} &amp;\\textbf{Soft} &amp; \\textbf{Executive}\\\\\\hline \\text{Q1} &amp; \\text{27300} &amp;\\text{20009} &amp;\\text{17602} &amp;\\text{9999}\\\\\\hline \\text{Q2} &amp; \\text{25222} &amp;\\text{19392} &amp; \\text{18445}&amp; \\text{8942}\\\\\\hline \\text{Q3} &amp; \\text{28976} &amp;\\text{22429} &amp; \\text{19544} &amp; \\text{10234}\\\\\\hline \\text{Q4} &amp;\\text{21012} &amp; \\text{18229} &amp; \\text{16595} &amp; \\text{10109}\\\\\\hline \\end{array}\\)\n<br> <br>Which product contributes the greatest fraction to the revenue of the company in that year? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Elegance</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Executive</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Smooth</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Soft</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Executive</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39616/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga06#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>A cube is built using 64 cubic blocks of side one unit. After it is built, one cubic block is removed from every corner of the cube. The resulting surface area of the body (in square units) after the removal is ________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>56</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>64</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>72</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>96</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>96</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39610/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga05#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>If 'relftaga' means carefree, 'otaga' means careful and 'fertaga' means careless, which of the following could mean 'aftercare'? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>zentaga</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>tagafer</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>tagazen</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>relffer</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>tagazen</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39609/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga04#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Archimedes said, \"Give me a lever long enough and a fulcrum on which to place it, and I will move the world.\"\n<br><br>\nThe sentence above is an example of a ____________ statement. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>figurative</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>collateral</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>literal</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>figurine</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>figurative</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39606/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga03#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>rewording of something written or spoken is a __________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>paraphrase</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>paradox</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>paradigm</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>paraffin</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>paraphrase</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39607/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga02#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Out of the following four sentences, select the most suitable sentence with respect to grammar and usage. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I will not leave the place until the minister does not meet me.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I will not leave the place until the minister doesn't meet me.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>I will not leave the place until the minister meet me.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>I will not leave the place until the minister meets me.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>I will not leave the place until the minister meets me.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39608/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga01#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}